Guide to the Salo W. Baron Papers, 1900-1980
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1: Correspondence, 70 linear ft. (140 boxes)
  - "L" 1944-1951 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    Jacob Landau, Carl Landauer, Franz Landsberger, M.R. Lehmann, Leibush Lehrer (Yiddish Scientific Institute), Manfred Lehmann, Artur Lelyveld, Louis Levinthal, Wolf Leslau, Isaac Levitats, Joseph Levitsky, Sanford Levy (Tb~ Judaeans), Leo Lichtblau
  - "L" 1944-1950 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    Joshua Liberman (Commission on New Approaches to American Jewish Education), Saul Lieberman, Anna Liebert, h.S. Linfield (Jewish Statistical Bureau), Adolph Lowe, Max Luft, H.L. Lurie
  - "M" 1945-1950 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Judah Magnes, Raphael Mahler, Maurice Mandelbaum, Jacob Marcus, Ralph Marcus, Isaac Marcuson, Margolies, Irving Mark, Max Markreich, Alexander Marx, Leo Mali, S.Z. Mayer
  - "M" 1944-1949 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    A. Menes, Menorah Association, Inc., Menorah Journal, Isidore Meyer, Attilio Milano, Norman Miller (Conference on Jewish Relations, Inc.), Yale Mintz, S. Mirsky, henry Moe, Monsky, Julian Morgenstern, henry Morgenthau (United Jewish Appeal)
  - "N" 1945-1950 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Judah Nadich, National Assembly for Labor Israel, National Conference of Jewish Social Welfare, National Council for Jewish Education, National Jewish Welfare Board, National Refugee Service, Inc.
  - "N" 1944-1949 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    Benjamin Nelson, Louis Newman, New Palestine (Carl Alpert), New York School of Social Work, R. Niebuhr, Edward Norman (American Fund for Palestinian Institutions, Inc.), Edward Nudelman
  - "0" 1944-1949 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Juhian Obermann, Toni Oelsner, Ohlgiesser (cousin), Adolph Oko, Fhany Orhinsky
  - "P" 1945-1949 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    R. Patai, henry Paul, Maurice Pekarsky, Moshe Perlmann, Sehig Periman, Fritz Peters, W. Pettit, Tova Pill, Gertrude Pill, Koppel Pinson, Herman Pohlack, H.M.Pomrenze, David de Sola Pool, Vladimir Pozner, Josef Preistag, Joachim Prinz, Charles Proffitt, Joseph Proskauer
  - "Ra-Ri" 1944-1950 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    Jacob Rabinowitz, 0. Rabinowicz, L. Rabinowitz, Emanuel Rackman, Isreal Rappaport (Research Institute in American Jewish Education), S. Rawidowicz, Ernest Reece, Manfred Reifer, Sydor Rey, Menachem Ribalow (hadoar)
  - "Ro-Ry" 1944-1950 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Jacob Robinson (Institute of Jewish Affairs), Joseph Rosen, James Rosenberg, Stuart Rosenberg, harry Rosenfield (Federal Security Agency), Isaac Rosengarten (The Jewish Forum), David Rosenstein, Nathan Rotenstreich, S. Rosowsky, Cecil Roth, harry Rubenstein
  - "Sa-Sc" 1945-1950 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    A.L. Sacher, Sachs, Gus Saron (South African Jewish Board of Deputies), Sharfstein, Joseph Schell, E.S. Schenkel, S. Scherzer, Lucy Schildkret, Ch. ~chirman, Pablo Scblanger, harry 'Schneiderman, Salman Schocken, Jacob Schwarz
  - "Se-Si" 1945-1949 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    henry Segal, Simon Seiden, Jerome Seidman (National Jewish Welfare Board), David Senator, Alfred Sendrey, Blanche Sheoard (American Zionist Emergency Council), Moshe Shuvass, Edmund Silberner, Eisig Silberschlag, Abba Hillel Silver, helen Silving, A. Simon
  - "5k-St' 1945-1951 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    Marshall Sklare, Skraynisrzorie(?), M. Smelansky, Isaiah Sonne (hebrew Union College), M. Spiegel, Shalom Spiegel, Frieda Spirer, Spiro, Joshua Stan, Eise Staudinger (American Committee for Emigre Scholars, Writers and Artists, Inc.), Michael Stavitsky (American Assoc. for Jewish Education), A. Steinberg (Worid Jewish Congress)
  - "St-Sz" 1945-1950 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    Harry Stern, herbert Strauss, Raphael Strauss, Stroock, Z. Szajkowski, M.A. Szuhwas
  - StarkandSussman 1944-1950 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - "T" 1945- 1950 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    Eugen Taubler, Tarnower Relief Committee and Vicinity, Arieh Tartakower (Worid Jewish Congress), Zvi Taubes, Israel Taslitt, R. Taubenschlag, Chaim Tchernowitz, Henry Tenenbaum, Joseph Tenenbaum (American Federation for Polish Jews), Chana Teichmann, Thomas Tobias
  - "T" 1938-1950 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service, Cehina Tuchfeld-Feller
  - "U" 1947-1950 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    Joseph Umanski, United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York, United Service for New Americans, Inc., Mark Uveeler (Yiddish Scientific Institute-YIVO)
  - "V" 1946-1950 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    Vajda, William Vickrey, Chemjo Vinaver, hans Vogelstein
  - "Wa-Wh" 1945-1949 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    Marcus Wald, Wallach, Louis Walls, Edward Warburg, Israel Wechsler, Frank Weil, Max Weinreich (Yiddish Scientific Institute), B.D. Weinryb, Weiss, Welt, Bessie Wesseh
  - "Wi-Wy" 1944-1949 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    Michael Wilenski, Mark Wischnitzer, Rachel Wischnitzer-Bernstein, Jonah Wise, Stephen Wise, Arnold Wiznitzer, Samuel Wohl, M. Wolozinsky, harold Wruble
  - "Y" 1944-1949 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    Yiddish Scientific Institute-YIVO (Leibush Lehrer, h.L. Lurie, Max Weinreich)
  - "Z" 1945-1950 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    Zeta Beta Tau, Zionist Organization of America (Carl Alpert, Abbie Brener, Israel Goldstein), Arthur Zuckerman, herman Zwillenberg
  - Academic Committee for the Hebrew University 1945-1947 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Werner Cahnman, Max Ascoli, Martin Buber, Samuel Finkel, harry Friedenwald, Oscar Gass, Louis Hacker, Max Horkheimer, I.L. Kandel, hans Kohn, Paul Laazarsfeld, Abba Lerner, Adolf Loewe, Ralph Marcus, Robert Nathan, S. Perlrnan, Arthur Schihler, Werner Senator, I.L. Sharfman, Leo Strauss, Arieh Tartakower
  - Academic Committee for the hebrew University 1944-1947 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Arieh Tartakower, Louis Wirth, Leo Wolman, G. Weih, minutes, Werner Cahnman, Leon Roth, membership lists
  - American Academy for Jewish Researchno date (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - American Academy for Jewish Research 1944-1950 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    Abraham Halkin, Boaz Cohen, Ethel Cohen (Mrs. Frank), Charies Proffitt, Leo Jung, A. Marx, Leo Strauss, minutes of meetings
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Incoming1941-1944 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    Berthold Ahtmann, V. Aptowitzer, American Philosophical Society, Fritz Bamberger, Lewis Bato, Rachel Wischnitzer-Bernstein, Joshua Bloch, B'nai B'rith, Abraham Brachman, Boaz Cohen, Ethel Cohen
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Incoming1942- 1943 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Ethel Cohen, Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Scholars, Joshua Finkel, Louis Finkelstein, A. Freimann, Solomon Gandz, h.L. Ginxberg, Nahum Glatzer, S. Goldenson, Israel Goldstein, A.S. Halkin, Michael higger, Maurice Jacobs (Jewish Publication Society of America),
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Incoming1942- 1943 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Incoming1941-1944 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Maurice Jacobs (Jewish Publication Society of America), Leo Jung, Louis Ginzberg, Aaron Kamerling, Guido Kisch, Anna Kieban, A. Kober, Alexander Kohut Memorial Foundation (A. Marx), J.B. Lightman, Raphael Mahler, Ralph Marcus
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Incoming1941- 1944 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Incoming1940- 1944 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    Ralph Marcus, Albert Martin, Alexander Marx, Miami Jewish Federation, Juhian Morgenstern, Abraham Neumann, M. Perlmann, David de Sola Pooh, S. Rosowski, Salmann Schocken, A. Sendry, Eisig Sihberschlag, Leo Strauss, Stroock, B. Taubler, Luitpold Walhach, Max Weinreich, D. Weinreich, Rachel Wischnitzer-Bernstein, Stephen Wise, h. Wohfson, Joseph Yasser
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Incoming1940- 1944 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Outgoing1941- 1944 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Berthohd Altman, Victor Aptowitzer, BJ. Bamberger, Fritz Bamberger, Morton Berman, Maurice B isgyer, Abraham Brachman, Armand Cohen, Boaz Cohen, Ethel Cohen (Mrs. Frank), E.G. Conklin, Betty Drury, Israel Efros, Louis Epstein, Joshua Finkel, Louis Finkehstein, Solomon Freehof, Aaron Freimann, Solomon Gandz, h.L. Ginsberg, Nahum Ghatzer, Samuel Goldenson, Solomon Goldman, Israel Goldstein, Solomon Grayzel, herman hailperin, A. hershman, Michael higger, Maurice Jacobs
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Outgoing1941- 1944 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Outgoing1941- 1943 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Maurice Jacobs, Leo Jung, Guido Kisch, Anna Kleban, Adolf Kober, Rebekah Kohut, Waldo Leland (American Council of Learned Societies), Saul Liebermann, Joshua Liebman, Ralph Marcus, Albert Martin, Alexander Marx, Juhian Morgenstern, Abraham Neumann, Moshe Perhman, David de Sola Pool, Joachim Prinz, Sahomo Rosowsky, Leon Roth, Joseph Shubow, Bisig Silberschlag, Abba hillel Silver, Leo Strauss, Eugen Taubler, Harry Torczyner, Luitpohd Wallach, Bernard Weinryb, Rachel Wischnitzer, Stephen Wise, harry Wolfson
  - American Academy for Jewish Research - Outgoing1941- 1943 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Maurice Jacobs, Leo Jung, Guido Kisch, Anna Kleban, Adolf Kober, Rebekah Kohut, Waldo Leland (American Council of Learned Societies), Saul Liebermann, Joshua Liebman, Ralph Marcus, Albert Martin, Alexander Marx, Julian Morgenstern, Abraham Neumann, Moshe Perhman, David de Sola Pool, Joachim Prinz, Sahomo Rosowsky, Leon Roth, Joseph Shubow, Bisig Silbersehlag, Abba hillel Silver, Leo Strauss, Eugen Taubler, Harry Torezyner, Luitpohd Wallach, Bernard Weinryb, Rachel Wischnitzer, Stephen Wise, harry Wolfson
  - American Association for Jewish Education 1947-1950 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Michael Stavitsky, Judah Pilch, Israel Chipkin
  - American Association for Jewish Education 1947-1950 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - American Friends of the hebrew University 1939-1944 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    Samuel Finkel, Isaac Mendelsohn, Tova Cohen, David Senator, harold Riegelman, A.S. Rosenbach, Joseph Schlossberg
  - American Friends of the hebrew University 1939-1944 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University 1944-1950 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    Rita Blume, Leo Schwarz, Israel Wechsler, Samuel Finkel
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University 1944-1950 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - American Friends of the hebrew University 1943-1949 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Samuel Finkel, Leo Scbwarz
  - American Friends of the hebrew University 1943-1949 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - American Jewish Committee, to 1947 1946-1947 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    Jacob Blaustein, Moths Fine, William Frankel, Irving Graef, J.B. Maller, Israel Rappoport, Joseph Proskauer, harry Schneiderman, Simon Segal, John Shawson, David Sher
  - American Jewish Committee, to 1947 1946-1947 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1950- 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    Moths Fine, Alan Stroock, John Slawson, Norman Goetz, Jacob Blaustein, henry Wiggins Bato, Rachel Wischnitzer-Bernstein, Joshua Bloch, B'nai B'rith, Abraham Brachman, Boaz Cohen, Ethel Cohen
  - American Jewish Committee, 1950- 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    Moths Fine, Alan Stroock, John Slawson, Norman Goetz, Jacob Blaustein, henry Wiggins
  - American Jewish Committee - Library of 1947-1950 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Moths Fine, Oscar handlin, Louis Finkelstein Information
  - American Jewish Committee - Library of 1945-1948 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Moths Fine, Louis Finkelstein, Oscar handhin, Information Jacob Marcus, Joseph Proskauer, harry Schneiderman, John Slawson, Alan Stroock, Thomas Tobias, J.B. Maller
  - American Jewish historical Society 1949- 1950 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Isidore Meyer, Joshua Bloch, Philip Goodman, Lee Friedman, Jacob Marcus,
  - American Jewish historical Society 1947- 1949 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    Isidore Meyer, minutes of meetings
  - Columbia University Administration - Incoming1937- 1944 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    John Krout, V. Ackerley, Frank Calhcott, S.B. Clough, Frank Fackenthal, Edward Fox, Philip Hayden, Carhton hayes, George Pegram
  - Columbia University Administration - Outgoing1938-1944 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    Frank Bowles, S.B. Clough, Austin Evans, Frank Fackenthal, W.B. Gentzler, Philip Hayden, Carlton hayes, George Pegram, Charles Williamson
  - Columbia University Administration 1945- 1950 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    George Pegram, W. B. Gentzler, herbert Schneider, John Wuorinen, Hans Rosenhaupt, James Pike, Frank Bowles, Frank Fackenthal, W.E. Gentzler, Philip hayden
  - Columbia University Administration 1947- 1949 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Albert Jacobs, Arthur Jefferies, John Krout, George Pegram
  - Columbia University Press - (Social & Religious 1945-1950 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    Charles Proffitt, Gretchen Scanlan, henry history and Maimonides) Wiggins, Isidore Abramowitz
  - Columbia University Press - Incoming1935-1940 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    Charles Proffitt, henry Wiggins, Fon Boardman, Donald Geddes
  - Columbia University Press - Outgoing1935-1938 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    Fon Boardman, Donald Geddes, Charles Proffitt, henry Wiggins
  - Commentary Jewish Review 1945-1950 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Elliot Cohen
  - Commission on European Jewish Cultural 1945-1947 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Hannah Arendt, Leo Baeck, Hugo Bergmann, Reconstruction ~JCR] ~ Philip Bernstein, S. Grand, J.H. Hillgring, Leo Jung, horace Kallen, Judah Magnes, Raphael Mahler, Jerome Michael, Ernest Munz, Koppel. Pinson, Joachim Prinz, Israel Rappoport, harry Rosenfield
  - Commission on European Jewish Cultural 1945-1947 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    harry Rosenfield, J. Schneersohn, David Werner, Reconstruction ~JCR] Senator, Joshua Starr, Eise Staudinger, herbert Strauss, Max Weinreich, minutes and reports
  - Conference on Jewish Material Claims Against 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    Maximilian Friede, Muriel Shapiro, Leon Shapiro, Germany Judah Shapiro, Isaac Shalom, Jacob Bhaustein, Naftahi horowitz, Andre Neher, Israel Schorr, H. Ehrhich
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR) - Incoming1940-1944 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Michael Alper, Ethel Cohen, Jacob Billikopf, Soh Bloom, Eli Cohen, Moths Cohen, Melvin Fagen, Oskar Fischer, Samuel Finkel, Theodor Gaster, Nahum Goldmann, Louis Gottschalk, Max Gottsachalk, Samuel Halperin, Jerome Hyman, Maurice Jacobs, J.M. Kaplan
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- Incoming1940-1943 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    Alex Landesco, h.L. Lurie, Jerome Michael, Koppel Pinson, David Rosenblum, harry Schneiderman, Abba hillel Silver, Joshua Starr, Jesse Steinhart, Mina Wagman, Stephen Wise
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- Outgoing1941-1944 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    Jacob Bilhikopf, Sol Bloom, A.J. Brachman, Eli Cohen, Moths Cohen, Abraham Duker, Elisha Friedman, Theodor Gaster, Nahum Gohdmann, Louis Gottschalk, horace Kallen, Hans Kohn, H.L. Lurie, Jerome Michael, Koppel Pinson, - David de Sola Pool, Jacob Robinson, David Rosenblum, harry Rosenfield, David Rosenstein, Cecil Roth, Abba Hillel Silver, Joshua Starr, Jesse Steinhart, Mina Wagman, Stephen Wise
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- General 1944-1946 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    Rosbyn Braun, Eli Cohen, Ethel Cohen, Frank Cohen, Moths Cohen, Ephraim Fisehoff, Beulah Fleischer, Jerome hyman, Elisha Friedman, Theodor Gaster, William Melniker
  - Conference on Jewish Relations ~CJRJ - General 1944- 1946 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    Miriam Lewis, Charles Liebman, H.L. Lurie, Jerome Michael, S.C. Kohs, Joachim Prinz, James Rosenberg, Harry Rosenfield, Charles Proffitt, James Senior, Susan Smith, Joshua Starr, Alan Stroock, Minna Wagman, Israel Wechsler
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- General 1945- 1950 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    Irene Steinberger, Jerome Michael, J.M. Kaplan, Rose Stern, Alan Siroock, Frank Weil, Israel Wechsler, Koppel Pinson, James Rosenberg, David Rosenstein, Lester Sehigman, Joshua Stan, Jerome hyman, Oskar Janowsky
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- General 1946- 1950 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Bernard Goldstein, Sada Gordon, Jerome hyman, Frank Trager, Leo Baeck, Joseph Blau, Abraham Brachman, Felix Cohen, Rose Cohen
  - Conference on Jewish Relations ~CJRJ - Werner 1955-1956 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Cahnman
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- Cohen 1949-1950 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Memorial Volume
  - Conference on Jewish Relations ~CJIR] - Leon Cooper1954 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- Jewish Social Studies1955-1956 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- David Rosenstein1945-1950 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations (CJR)- David Rosenstein1954-1955 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations ~CJRII - Welfare 1945-1951 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    Funds
  - Conference on Jewish Social Studies (CJSS] - Meir 1954-1957 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    Marvin Lowenthal, Meir Ben-horn, Oskar Ben-Horn Book Rabinowiex, Werner Cahnman, Bertha Grnner, Abraham Duker, Bernard Goldstein, Leon Cooper
  - Congress for Jewish Culture 1955 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Congress of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds 1946- 1950 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    Benjamin Rosenberg, Alan Lowenstein, Stanley Myers, S.P. Goldberg, h.L. Lurie, Isador Lubin, William Avrunin, Philip Bernstein
  - Dess and Talan 1952-1956 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Encyclopedia hebraica (Israel) 1954-1957 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    S. Katz, K. Katzenelsohn, K. horowitz, A. Pelia, Joseph Bar-Lev, Cecil Roth
  - Ford Foundation 1953-1956 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Friedman, Philip 1951-1955 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - hadassah 1954-1957 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    Esther Gottesman, Leo Schwarz, Hannah Goldberg, Rebecca Shulman
  - Hadoar 1955-1958 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    M. Meisels, David Epstein
  - Hebrew Union College - Jewish Institute of Religion 1954-1955 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    Nelson Glueck, Frank Weil, Reconstruction Magnes, Leo Schwarz
  - Theodore herzl Institute 1957 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    Emanuel Neumann, Raphael Patai
  - International Commission on a Scientific 1954-1957 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    Guy Metraux, Cultural History of Mankind
  - Jewish Agency for Palestine 1954-1957 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Sulamith Schwartz, Samuel Blumenfield, Nahum Goldmann, Ben halpern
  - Jewish Book Council 1953, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Community - Incoming1941-1942 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Solomon Grayzel, Herbert hahn, Maurice Jacobs, herbert Solow
  - Jewish Community - Outgoing1940-1942 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Solomon Grayzel, Maurice Jacobs, Alexander Marx, herbert Solow
  - Jewish Cultural Reconstruction and Restitution 1947-1949 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Edward Warburg, Joshua Starr, John Shawson, Committee Irene Steinberger, herbert Strauss, Koppel Pinson, Jerome Michael, Robert Murphy, David de Soha Pool, Oskar Rabinowicz, Cecil Roth, G. Schohem, Hannah Arendt, Max Gruenwald, Bernard hehler, Judah Shapiro, Noel hemmendinger, J.h. hilldring, Leo Jung, Adolf Kober, Bernard Kolb, Isaac Lewin, Rose Cohen, Solomon Freehof
  - Jewish Cultural Reconstruction and Restitution 1948-1950 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Max Gruenewald, Meir Ben-horn, C. Sidney Committee Bertheim, Brnno Blau, A.G. Brotman, Maurice Boukstein, Hannah Arendt, Leo Baeck, Jacob Rosenheim
  - Jewish Cultural Reconstruction [JCR] 1948- 1949 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Joshua Starr
  - Jewish Cultural Reconstruction [JCR] - 1954-55 1954-1957 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Hannah Arendt, Koppel Pinson, Hans Lamm, Germania Judaica, Bertha Gruner, Oskar Rabinowicz, G. Scholem
  - Jewish Cultural Reconstruction [JCR] - Jewish 1954- (Box 44, Folder 2)
    1956 Annual Report, Max Gruenewald, Saul Kagan, Restitution Successor Organization ~JRSO] minutes
  - Jewish Education Committee 1954-1956 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Israel Chipkin
  - Jewish History Publications, Inc. 1954-1959 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    B. Netanyahu, Jacob Marcus, Israel halprin, T. Sondov, Ben Zion Dinur, Abraham Neumann
  - Jewish Publication Society of America 1945- 1950 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Solomon Grayzel, Maurice Jacobs
  - Jewish Publication Society of America 1954-1958 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Lesser Zussman, Solomon Grayzel, Louis Leventhal, Edwin Wolf, Jacob Marcus
  - Jewish Publication Society of America 1958-1961 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Solomon Grayzel, Maurice Jacobs, Lesser Zussman, Sol Satinsky, Abraham Pines, Leo Strauss, Mordecai Kaplan
  - Jewish Publication Society of America 1944- 1949 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    Solomon Grayzel, Maurice Jacobs, Louis Levinthal, minutes
  - Jewish Publication Society of America 1947 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    Solomon Grayzel, minutes
  - Jewish Social Studies ~JSS] - Incoming1937-1942 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    Rachel Wischnitzer, Theodore Gaster, Michael Alper, Ethel Cohen, Moths Cohen, Melvin Fagen, Samuel Feigin, Louis Finkelstein, Maurice Jacobs, Otto Kleppner, Jacob Marcus, Koppel Pinson
  - Jewish Social Studies ~JSS] - Incoming1937-1941 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    Koppel Pinson, Michael Scheler, Eisig Silberschlag, Joshua Starr, Mina Wagman, Luitpold Wallach, Rachel Wischnitzer-Bernstein
  - Jewish Social Studies ~JSSI - Outgoing1938-1943 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    Jacob Billikopf, Mrs. Frank Cohen, Moths Cohen, Melvin Fagen, Louis Finkelstein, Aron Freimann, Nahum Glatzer, Maurice Jacobs, Koppel Pinson, Cecil Roth, Eisig Silberschlag, - Abba hillel Silver, Joshua Starr, Rachel Wisehnitzer
  - Jewish Social Studies ~JSS] 1945-1951 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    Oskar Janowsky, Harold Jonas, Bernard Weinryb, Koppeh Pinson, Jerome Gladstein, Irene Steinberger, Oskar Rabinowitz, Samuel Rosensohn, Alexander Marx, Joshua Stan, Max Weinreich, Rose Cohen, Hans Kohn
  - Jewish Theological Seminary - Students 1955-1958 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Kohut Memorial Volume 1935-1936 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    Bernard heller, Rebekah Kohut, George Kohut, V. Aptowitzer, Majer Balaban, Herbert Bloom, A. Buechler, Israel Davidson, Alvin Johnson, Guido Kisch, Louis Finkelstein, Solomon Gandz, M. Gaster, Leo Baeck, Maurice Jacobs, Julius Grodinsky (Jewish Publication Society of America)
  - Kohut Memorial Volume 1934-1936 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    Julius Grodinsky, Max Kohler, Rebekah Kohut, Samuel Krauss, Ralph Marcus, Alexander Marx, Oscar Rosner, Cecil Roth, h. Torczyner, Stephen Wise, h. Wolfson, H. Zimmeis, Majer Balaban, A. Buehler, Louis Finkelstein, Richard Gottheil, Bernhard Heller, Max Kohler, Joseph Stroock
  - Maimonides Octocentennial Volume - Incoming1940- 1943 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    Joshua Finkel, Louis Finkelstein, Maurice Jacobs, Rebekah Kohut, Ida Lynn, Alexander Marx, Richard MeKeon, Max Meyerhof, Charles Proffitt, Georgia Read, Joshua Starr, Leo Strauss
  - Maimonides Octocentennial Volume - Outgoing1938- 1941 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    Emil Damask, Joshua Finkel, A.S. hallcin, Rebekah Kohut, Ida Lynn, Alexander Marx, Richard McKeon, Max Meyerhof, Charles Proffitt, Leo Strauss, henry Wiggins
  - National Jewish Welfare Board 1945-1950 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    Bernard Carp, Oskar Janowsky, S.D. Gershovitz, Louis Kraft, Benjamin Rabinowitz, Frank Weil
  - National Jewish Welfare Board 1945- 1948 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    Frank Weil, JWB survey, minutes, David de Sola Pool
  - Research Institute on Peace 1940-1941 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    Moths Cohen, Max Gottschallc, American Jewish Committee, CJR, Guido Kisch, minutes
  - Schocken Books 1948-1949 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    NahumGlatzer
  - South Africa 1943-1947 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    South African Jewish Board of Deputies, Gus Saron
  - Training Bureau-- Syllabi, Reports and Correspondence to 19491947- 1949 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service, Correspondence to 1949 Abraham Duker, course outiines, memoranda
  - Training Bureau-- Syllabi, Reports and Correspondence to 19491947- 1949 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    Memoranda, course outlines, Training Bureau for Correspondence to 1949 Jewish Communal Service
  - Training Bureau, 1950-1951 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Samuel Goldsmith, Jewish Welfare Fund, Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service, memoranda, course outlines
  - Training Bureau 1948- 1951 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    Training Bureau for Jewish Communal Service, Abraham Duker, memoranda, course outlines, issues of Palestine Affairs
  - Miscellaneous 1946-1949 (Box 48, Folder 2)